rapradar.com 2013-09-21

# Rap Radar :: Privacy Policy

**Effective March 9, 2009:**

This privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy’) of RapRadar.com , owned and/or operated by Makavelliot, LLC (the “Company”) describes the privacy practices for the Company’s web site, located at the domain name [http://www.rapradar.com](http://www.rapradar.com/) (the “Site”).  The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you when you visit this Site, information we may receive from third parties or affiliates, how we may use that information, whether we disclose that information to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to correct, the information.  By using this Site, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy.  DO NOT USE THIS SITE IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

The Company supports the protection of individual privacy and strives to help its supporters and other visitors of the Site protect their privacy while using our Site.  The Company wants to make your online experience satisfying and safe.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites that are accessible through this Site.  Please be aware that any advertisers, third party blogs, sponsors, affiliated entities and other third-party websites accessible through this Site may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices.  We are not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties.  You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing personally identifiable information through such linked websites.

**MINORS**

The Site is a general audience site and does not knowingly collect information from children under 13 years of age.

**MODIFICATION OF THE PRIVACY POLICY**

From time to time the Company may modify this Privacy Policy to reflect industry initiatives or changes in the law, our information collection and use practices, the features of the Site, or technology, and such modifications shall be effective upon posting by the Company on the Site.  Your continued use of the Site after the Company posts a revised Privacy Policy signifies your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy.  It is therefore important that you review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure you are updated as to any changes.  If the Company materially changes its practices regarding collection or use of your information, your information will continue to be governed by the Privacy Policy under which it was collected unless you have been provided notice of, and have not objected to, the change.

**COLLECTION OF YOUR INFORMATION**

You do not have to provide any personally identifiable information to use this Site.  We collect no personal information, such as an individual’s name, address, phone number, or email address, about you unless you voluntarily participate in an activity on the Site that asks for personal **** information.  For example, if you wish to receive our newsletters, you must provide your email address **.** If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will not affect your ability to use any other features of our Site.

We collect information from applications or personal correspondence, such as emails or letters that you send to us.  We may ask you to voluntarily provide us with personal information on this Site.  If personal information is requested on the Site or volunteered by the user, state and federal law may protect it.  However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

Any personal information or Content that you voluntarily disclose on the Site (such as on discussion boards, forums, bulletin boards, in messages, social networking and chat areas, or other message and communications features that may be offered on the Site (“Interactive Areas”)) becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others.

We may collect some information about your visit to the Site.  This information may include:

1\. The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used but not the email address. The Internet Protocol Address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet Service Provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol Address to direct Internet traffic to you;

2\. The type of browser you used;

3\. The date and time that you visited the Site; and,

4\. The web pages or services you accessed at the Site.

The information we collect or store is used to improve the content of our web services and to help us understand how people are using our services.

We may offer the ability for you to email us.  If during your visit to the Site you send an email to us, the following information will be collected: (1) the email address you used in sending the email; and, (2) the contents of the email.

We use your email to respond appropriately.  This may be to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to further improve the Site, or to forward the email to another agency for appropriate action.

To better serve our users we may use “cookies” to customize your browsing experience with us. Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your web browser.  They provide a method of distinguishing among visitors to the Site.

Cookies created on your computer by using this Site do not contain personally identifying information and do not compromise your privacy or security.  We use the cookie feature only to store a randomly generated identifying tag on your computer.  You can refuse the cookie or delete the cookie file from your computer by using any of the widely available methods.  Our services are provided in such a way that the use of cookies is not mandatory.

In addition to cookies, the Company may use other now known or later developed technologies, including web beacons or web bugs, to assist the Company in observing the behavior of users visiting the Site.  These technologies access individual user information but the information is used only to compile aggregated statistics about the Site’s usage.

**USE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

If you submit personally identifiable information to us through the Site, we use your personal information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the general and personalized features and functionality of the Site and as generally part of the services offered on the Site, and to process any flagging activity or correspondence you send to us.

We may use the information collected from you to provide services which you have requested from us.  We may also use your personal information to send you targeted messages, publications, news, newsletters and information about events, special offers, and promotions.  We may also use third-party service providers to send and distribute email and to perform other marketing and support functions.  We may use information we automatically collect from you to improve the content of this Site, to enhance users’ experiences when visiting this Site, and to customize the content and layout of this Site for each individual user.

**SHARING YOUR INFORMATION**

We may share your personal information with our affiliated entities (“Affiliate”), or with select third parties who offer goods or services we think may be of interest to you.  From time to time, we may partner with other organizations or companies to provide co-sponsored or co-branded promotions, services or events and may share your personal information with our co-sponsor.  Use of shared information is subject to third parties’ policies.

We may also share personal information with: (i) service providers performing services on our behalf; other businesses with which we partner or which we carefully select to offer you products, services, and promotions through our website or offline; and (ii) other third parties in limited circumstances, such as complying with legal requirements, preventing fraud, and protecting the safety of our users.

We may transfer your personal information to any successor company to the Company, including, without limitation, in connection with a merger, reorganization, or sale of all or substantially all of the Company’s assets.

We also may share with third parties aggregated demographic and statistical information that is not personally identifiable.

The Company also may disclose an individual’s personal information to:

•  a person who in the reasonable judgment of the Company is seeking the information as an agent of the individual;

•  a company or individual employed or hired by the Company to perform functions on its behalf, such as but not limited to, a company or individual hired to provide services in connection with the Site, to communicate news or deliver promotional materials via email and direct mail, or to develop, enhance, market or provide any of the Company’s services;

•  in situations where sharing or disclosing your information is required in order to offer you products or services you desire; and

•  a third party or parties, where the individual consents to such disclosure, or where disclosure is required or permitted by law.

The Company may be required to use or disclose your information in connection with a legal action or other proceeding, including without limitation, in response to a court order or a subpoena.  We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request.

The Company may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, social networking and/or news groups available to our users through the Site.  Some of these forums require registration.  Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

The Company employees, agents and contractors must have a business reason to obtain access to your information and may share your personal information only with those who help us manage or provide Site services (for example, message board administration, statistical analyses, data processing), or with outside contractors, agents or sponsors who help us with the administration of Site service items.  These outside contractors, agents or sponsors may temporarily store some information on their servers, but they may only use your personal information to provide the Company with a specific service and not for any other purpose.  The Company may also provide your personal information to a third party in those instances where you have chosen to receive certain information and have been notified that the fulfillment of such a request requires the sharing of your personal information.

**OPT OUT**

If at any time you wish to stop receiving emails, newsletters or mailings from the Company or you would like to be excluded from the sharing of your information to any of our affiliates or other third parties, please let us know by sending us an email to unsubscribe@rapradar.com with the phrase “Privacy Opt-out” in the subject line, or writing to us at the address provided below.  This opt-out provision shall in no way limit the Company’s rights set forth above to disclose your information to enforce or preserve our rights under the law.

**STORING YOUR INFORMATION**

The Company is committed to protecting the security of any personal information you provide to us.  If we collect personally identifiable information **,** we will safeguard such information according to our established security standards and procedures.  After you have submitted your information online, we recommend that you end your browser session before leaving your computer.

In spite of these protections, the Company cannot guarantee the security of any data submitted over the Internet.  After your information reaches the Company, however, it is stored on servers (or in the case of information received from you in person, in writing or over the phone, in storage areas) protected by procedures and technology designed to block reasonably foreseeable intrusions by unauthorized third parties.

**THIRD-PARTY LINKS**

The Site may list or contain links to other websites.  The Company is not responsible for the privacy practices of such websites and will not be a party to or responsible for any transactions between you and such third parties.  We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit.  This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by the Company.

**CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

If you are a California resident, you have the right to request information from us regarding the manner in which we share certain categories of personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, in addition to the rights set forth above.  Under California law, you have the right to send us a request at the designated address listed below to receive the following information:

1\. The categories of information we disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year;

2\.  the names and addresses of the third parties that received that information; and

3\. if the nature of the third party’s business cannot be determined from their name, examples of the products or services marketed.

This information may be provided in a standardized format that is not specific to you.  The designated email address for these requests can be found at: privacy@rapradar.com.

**CONTACT US**

If you would like to update or correct your information or modify your communication preferences, or if you have questions regarding our Privacy Policy or the use of information collected, you can contact us by email:  privacy@rapradar.com or by writing to us at: Rap Radar, 400 Garden City Plaza, Suite 202, Garden City, NY 11530 – Attention:  Privacy Policy
